[ Background Conversations ]
[背景对话]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Welcome to What's New
&gt;&gt; 大家好 欢迎来到
in LLVM.
“What’s New in LLVM（LLVM 的新内容）”
I'm Devin, an engineer on the
我是 Devin 是一名工程师
Program Analysis Team.
来自程序分析团队
We've got a lot of great, new
今天 我们有很多非常不错的新
features to tell you about
功能和大家
today.
分享
We'll start by introducing you
我们首先会介绍
to availability checking for
Objective-C 的
Objective-C.
可用性检查
This will help you safely deploy
可用性检查能够帮助用户安全配置
your apps back to older OS's.
App 到旧的系统中
Then, we'll describe new static
然后我们将介绍新的静态
analyzer checks and compiler
分析器检查和编译器
warnings to help you find bugs.
警告功能 来帮助你找到 Bug
We'll dive into some fantastic,
接着我们将讨论为 C++ 开发人员
new features for C++ developers,
打造的一些绝妙的新功能
including a tour of refactoring
包括 Xcode 代码中的
support for C++ in Xcode, and
C++ 重构支持
wrap up with an update on
最后
link-time optimization.
介绍链接时间优化的更新
Let's start with availability
让我们先从可用性检查
checking.
开始说起
Every major OS release comes
每一次主要的 OS 发布时
with great, new features, and
我们都会介绍一些非常棒的新功能
your customers expect you to
你的顾客希望你能把
adopt these APIs in your apps.
这些 API 运用到你们的 App 上
But you still have to support
但你仍须支持
your users on older OS's where
使用旧 OS 的顾客 虽然
those APIs aren't available.
这些 API 在旧的 OS 中无法使用
On our platforms, we support
在我们的平台上 我们支持
backwards deployment by
反向配置 通过
separating the Base SDK version
将基础 SDK 版本
from the deployment target
从配置目标版本隔离
version.
来实现
What this means is that you will
也就是说
always compile against the
即使在旧的系统中进行配置时
newest SDK, even when deploying
你也可以利用最新的
back to older OS's.
SDK 进行编译
So for example, in Xcode 9, you
举个例子 在 Xcode 9 中
use the iOS 11 SDK, and if your
如果你使用 iOS 11 SDK  且你的
app only targets iOS 11, you'll
App 只针对 iOS 11
use that as the deployment
你会把它也作为配置
target as well.
目标
But I know a lot of you will
但我知道在座的很多人
want to support your users on
希望在 iOS 10 中支持你们的用户
iOS 10 to give them a chance to
给用户一个机会
upgrade.
进行升级
To do that, you can go to your
要这么做的话 你可以前往
Build settings and select 10.0
“Build Settings（构建设置）”
for your deployment target.
选择 10.0 作为配置目标
This is a promise on the part of
这可以保证你的 App
your app that it will support
能够支持
all versions of iOS 10 and
iOS 10 以及更新系统的
greater.
所有版本
Now, this can be tricky because
这其实有点投机取巧
it's only safe to call APIs that
因为只有调用
are actually available on the
系统真正支持的 API
running OS.
才安全
If you call in newer API on an
如果你在旧系统中调用新版本 API
older OS, then your app could
那么你的 App 很可能
crash or have other unexpected
崩溃 或出现其他意外
behavior.
行为
In the past, we've recommended
过去 我们推荐
querying the Objective-C runtime
查询 Objective-C 运行时
to determine whether an API is
来确定 API 是否
available.
适用
But this was easy to get wrong
但是这个方法很容易出错
or even forget, and it was hard
或被忘记 而且很难
to test.
进行测试
Further, it required a different
而且 它需要不同的
syntax for checking each of
语法来检查每项
globals, functions, classes,
全局变量 函数 类
instance methods, and class
实例方法和
methods.
类方法
Now, those of you using Swift
你们之中在使用 Swift 的人
may be wondering, what's the big
可能会想 这有什么
deal here?
大不了的吗
Swift has a unified syntax,
Swift 有一个统一的语法
#available, for querying API
#available 可在运行时用于查询 API
availability at runtime, and the
的可用性 而且
compiler can even catch missing
编译器甚至可以在编译时
availability checks at compile
捕捉缺失的可用性
time.
检查
For more information on
想要了解更多
availability in Swift, you
关于 Swift 可用性的信息请
should check out the Swift in
前往 WWDC 2015 中的“Swift in Practice”
Practice talk from WWDC 2015.
以了解更多
Today we brought Swift-style
现在我们将 Swift 类的
availability checking to
可用性检查带入了
Objective-C.
Objective-C
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
I would love to tell you about
我想为大家介绍一下
it.
这个功能
So suppose you have an app that
假设你有一个 App
you're deploying back to iOS 10
你想把它配置回 iOS 10 中
and you decide to take advantage
并且你决定利用
of the fantastic, new face
iOS 11 提供的
detection APIs from the Vision
Vision 框架中全新的
framework in iOS 11.
人脸检测 API
When you add these APIs to your
当你将这些 API
app and then build, you will now
添加至 App 并构建时
get a compiler warning telling
你会收到一个编译器警告
you that these APIs are only
告诉你这些 API 只
available in iOS 11 or newer.
适用于 iOS 11 或更新的系统
You can address these warnings
你可以
by using the new @available
通过使用新的@available 结构
construct to query for API
查询 API 可用性
availability.
来处理这些警告
This will return true when iOS
当 iOS 11 API 适用时
11 APIs are available.
@available 结构返回值为真
It's safe to call them.
这种情况下调用 API 很安全
And if they're not, you can
如果不适用 你可以
provide a fallback.
提供一个 Fallback（回退）
Let's take a closer look at the
我们来仔细看看
query.
查询功能
As I mentioned, on iOS 11 or
我刚刚提过 在 iOS 11系统或
greater, this will return true.
更新的系统里 它的返回真为值
The star is required.
这个星号是必须的
It indicates that on all other
它表明在其他所有
platforms, the query always
平台上 查询总会
returns true.
返回真值
What this means is that if you
也就是说 如果你
decide to port your app to
决定将 App 转移至
another platform -- say, macOS
另一个平台 比如 macOS
-- then by default it will take
那么 默认情况下
advantage of the new face
它会利用这个新的
detection APIs.
人脸检测 API
Of course, the compiler will
当然 如果 API
still warn you if your port to
不适用于该 macOS 支持的
macOS supports an earlier
先前配置目标
deployment target where those
编译器
APIs aren't available.
依然会发出警告
So you'll need to add a check.
所以你需要检查一下
Once you've been working with
一旦你开始使用
availability for a while, you
可用性这个功能
will find that it's really
你会发现
useful to write entire methods
编写一个只能在 iOS 11
that will only be called on iOS
或更新系统上调用的一整套方法
11 or greater.
真的非常有用
You can annotate these methods
你可以使用全新的
with the new API availability
API 可用性宏
macro.
注释这些方法
Then, inside that method, you
然后 在这个方法中
don't need to use @available to
无须使用 @available
check for availability, but
检查可用性
anyone who calls the method will
但是调用该方法的人
need to do so.
需要使用 @available
Otherwise, they'll get a
否则 他们会收到一个
warning.
警告
You can similarly apply this to
你还可以把这个功能应用于
entire classes.
整个类
Then, you don't need to use
而且 你无须
@available inside the class, but
在该类中使用 @available
anyone who instantiates it will
但实例化该类的人
need to do so.
都需要使用 @available
Now, availability checking is
现在 可用性检查
not just for Objective-C.
不仅仅用于 Objective-C 中
We also support C and C++ with
通过内建可用性查询
the builtin available query.
我们还支持 C 和 C++
This acts exactly like
这里的用法和
@available.
@available 完全一样
It has the same syntax.
它们有一样的语法
It just has a different name
只是名称不同
that's compatible with C and
且名称与 C 和 C++
C++.
兼容
You can also use the API
你还可以
availability macro in C, but you
在 C 中使用 API 可用性宏
will need to include the os
但须要包括
availability.h header to get
头文件 才能
access to it.
访问
And you can even annotate your
你甚至可以对你的
C++ class definitions.
C++ 类的定义进行注释
All right, so how's this going
那么 我们具体
to work in practice?
应该要怎样做呢
For existing projects, we will
对于现有的工程
warn starting with APIs
我们不建议一开始就使用
introduced in iOS 11, tvOS 11,
iOS 11  Apple TVOS 11
macOS 10.13, and watchOS 4.
macOS 10.13 和 watchOS 4 引入的 API
APIs from older SDKs will not be
老版本 SDK 的 API
checked at compile time.
在编译时不会被检查
This means that you won't need
也就是说你无须
to change any existing code, but
改变任何现有代码
if you do decide to adopt the
但如果你决定采用
new APIs, you'll need to use
新的 API 你需要使用
@available to check for them.
@available 检查新的 API
We think this is the best and
我们认为这是最佳
safest way to check for
也是最安全的
availability, and so we highly
可用性检查方法 所以我们强烈
encourage you to use it.
推荐大家使用
For new projects, all APIs will
对于新项目 所有 API
be checked at compile time.
都会在编译时被检查
This means you'll need to use
也就是说你在配置目标
@available for all APIs
下面引入的所有 API
introduced after your deployment
都需要使用
target.
@available
Existing projects can opt in to
现有项目也可以选择
this all-API behavior by going
这种全 API 行为
to the Build settings and
前往构建设置
selecting Yes (All Versions) for
在“Unguarded availability”一栏
the Unguarded availability
选择“Yes (All Versions)”
setting.
即可实现
This is going to make it a lot
这个方法使
easier to safely deploy your
在旧的系统中安全配置 App
apps back to older OS's.
变得更加简单
So that's availability checking.
以上就是关于可用性检查的介绍
You could say it's now
你可以说它现在在
@available for C, C++, and
C C++ 和 Objective-C 中
Objective-C.
都“@available（可用）”了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
All right, let's move on to the
好的 我们继续来看
static analyzer.
静态分析器
The analyzer is great at
这个分析器擅长
catching hard-to-reproduce
捕捉难以重现的
edge-case bugs, and it can even
极端情况 Bug 甚至可以
show you the sequence of
展示导致 Bug 的
corner-case events that led to
极端事件的
those bugs.
序列
Today I'm going to tell you
今天 我会向大家
about three new checks that
介绍三种
we've added to the analyzer: a
我们添加至该分析器的新的检查方法
check for suspicious comparison
NSNumber 可疑比较检查
of NSNumber, a check for use of
实例变量中
dispatch once on instance
dispatch_once() 使用
variables, and a check for
检查 以及 NSMutable 中
auto-synthesized copy properties
自动综合的
of NSMutable type.
copy 属性检查
A particularly pernicious bug is
有一个致命的 Bug 是
to mistakenly compare an
错误地将
NSNumber pointer value to the
NSNumber 指针值
scalar zero because this
与标量“0”相比较 因为
actually compares to nil and not
这个操作实际上是将指针值与 nil 相比较
the zero NSNumber instance.
而不是 NSNumber 实例的“0”
Here's an example of how this
我给大家举个例子说明为什么
can be a problem.
这个问题很严重
In the hasPhotos method, the
在 hasPhotos 方法中
programmer intends to return no
编程者想要返回“no”
when the photo album is empty,
如果相册是空的
but because they're comparing
但是因为他们
the photo count to nil, this
将照片数量计为“nil” 这个结果
will actually return yes, even
实际上将返回“yes” 即使
when photo count holds the zero
照片数量
NSNumber instance.
在 NSNumber 实例中计为“0”
And so the analyzer will now
所以这时分析器
warn about this.
会发出警告
You can fix this error by
你可以通过
instead calling the integerValue
调用 integerValue 属性
property to compare integers to
进行整数之间的比较
integers.
来纠正这个错误
This is safe.
这个方法很安全
There's a similar problem with
布尔运算的隐式变换
implicit conversions to Booleans
有一个类似的问题
because these also check for nil
因为也是检查“nil”
and not the zero number.
而不是数字“0”
This method counts the number of
这个方法计算
faces in a photo, and since this
一张照片上出现的人脸数量 鉴于这项
is an expensive operation, it
操作成本较高
returns early if they've already
如果已经计算过数量
been counted.
那么值会及早返回
But someone reading this code
但是读到这个代码的人
might find it ambiguous.
可能会觉得它有歧义
Did the programmer intend to
如果人脸数量不是“nil”或“0”
return early if face count was
编程者是否打算
non-nil or non-zero?
提前返回
The analyzer will now warn about
分析器现在可以
this kind of ambiguity.
针对这类歧义发出警告
In this case, the programmer
在这种情况下 编程者
meant non-nil, and so she can
如果想让结果为非 nil  她可以
express her intent directly in
将她的想法直接在代码中表达出来
the code and silence the
并沉默分析器的警告
analyzer warning by adding the
这可以通过明确地添加比较
comparison explicitly.
来实现
You can control the level of
你可以在构建设置中
this check in your Build
控制检查
setting.
等级
If you choose Yes (Aggressive),
如果选择“Yes (Aggressive)”
then the analyzer will warn when
那么分析器在不确定你是否犯错时
it's not sure that you've made a
就会生成警告
mistake, but it does think your
但是它不认为你的
code is ambiguous.
代码是有歧义的
Let's move on to dispatch once.
接下来我们介绍 dispatch_once()
Grand Central Dispatch provides
多线程优化技术（GCD）提供
a fantastic API, dispatch once,
了一个非常棒的 API  dispatch_once()
that guarantees that a block is
它保证了一个块
called once and only once.
会被调用一次 并且只有一次
It is really useful for safely
它对于安全地
initializing shared global
初始化共享全局状态
state.
非常有用
In this example, the programmer
在这个例子中 编程者
uses it to load and initialize a
利用它加载和初始化
shared array of photos.
一个共享照片数列
The first argument to dispatch
dispatch_once() 的第一个参数
once is the address of a
是对一个特殊变量
variable of a special type,
的声明
dispatch once t.
dispatch_once_t
Grand Central Dispatch uses this
GCD 利用这一点
to make sure that the block is
确保代码块
only called once.
只被调用一次
Now, it's really important that
有一点很重要
this variable be either a static
就是该变量要么是静态变量
or a global variable.
要么是全局变量
That's because if it's ever been
这是因为 如果出现
the case that the variable held
该变量
a non-zero value in the past,
过去的值是非零的情况
then Grand Central Dispatch
GCD 可能无法保证
might not be able to make the
在多线代码中进行
once and only once guarantee in
有且只有一次
multithreaded code.
的执行
What this means is that it's not
也就是说
safe to use dispatch once t in
在实例变量
instance variables or, indeed,
或其他任何可能
in any other memory on the heap
被复用过的堆内存中
that might have been reused.
使用 dispatch_once_t 是不安全的
And so the analyzer will now
所以分析器现在会
warn about this.
因此生成警告
To fix this, you can use your
为了解决这个问题 你可以使用你
favorite non-recursive lock.
最爱的非递归锁
Here I'll use NSLock, but you
这里我使用 NSLock 但你
could use OSUnfairLock or a
可以使用 OSUnfairLock 或
pthread mutex as well.
pthread_mutex
After acquiring the lock, check
获取锁后 检查
to see whether the data's
数据是否已经
initialized, and if not,
初始化 如果没有
initialize it, and then don't
对数据进行初始化 不要
forget to release the lock.
忘了释放锁
This will guarantee that the
这样能确保
data's initialized once and only
数据初始化有且只有一次
once, exactly like you expect.
完全符合你的预期
Finally, I'm going to tell you
最后 我向大家
about a check that we've added
介绍我们添加至
for auto-synthesized copy
NSMutable 类自动综合的
properties of NSMutable types.
copy 属性的检查
Copy properties call the copy
copy 属性利用传入值调用其 setter 的
method in their setter on the
copy 方法
passed-in value to story a copy.
来构建一个 copy
But calling copy on a mutable
但是调用 copy 可变数组
array results in an immutable
会导致 copy
copy.
不可变
Here's how this can be a
我来解释一下为什么
problem.
这是一个问题
It, this method tries to reset
这个方法试图
the photos property by setting
重置照片属性
it to an empty mutable array and
通过将其设置为一个空的可变数组
then adding in a single photo.
然后添加一张单独的照片来实现
Unfortunately, this will lead to
但是 这会导致
a really nasty surprise at
运行时出现意外
runtime because you can't add an
因为你无法
object to an immutable array.
将一个对象添加至不可变数组
You'll get an exception.
你会获得一个异常
The analyzer will now warn you
这时分析器会发出警告
about these kinds of properties
告知你这些属性
to help you prevent this runtime
帮助你防止运行
exception.
异常
The fix here is simple.
解决方法很简单
All you need to do is write the
你只须明确写出 setter
setter explicitly to have it
使其调用
call mutableCopy.
mutableCopy
This guarantees that your
这可以确保你的
property always holds a mutable
属性始终是可变
array.
数组
So those are just three of the
以上介绍的就是
new checks that we've added to
今年我们添加至
the analyzer this year.
分析器的 3 种新的检查方法
You should run it on your code.
你应该在代码中些运行一下试试
It will help you find bugs.
它们会帮助你找到 Bug
To do that, choose Analyze from
为了使用这个功能 大家可以从
Xcode's Product menu.
Xcode 的“Product（产品） ”菜单中选择“Analyze（分析）”
You could even have Xcode run
你甚至可以让 Xcode 在每次编译中运行
the analyzer on every compile by
分析器 可以通过
going to your Build settings and
前往构建设置
enabling Analyze During 'Build.'
选择“Analyze During ‘Build’”来实现
This will help you catch your
这可以帮助你
bugs early and often.
及早并时常捕捉 Bug
If you're interested in other
如果你对其他
tools to help you find bugs, I
发现 Bug 的工具感兴趣
highly encourage you to check
我强烈推荐在线观看
out finding bugs using Xcode
“Finding Bugs Using Xcode Runtime Tools
runtime tools online.
（使用 Xcode 运行时工具寻找 Bug）”
So that's what's new in the
以上介绍的就是我们
analyzer.
在分析器方面的新功能
I'm not going to hand it over to
接下来我把时间交给
Duncan, who will tell us about
Duncan 他会向大家介绍
new compiler warnings.
新的编译器警告功能
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Devin.
&gt;&gt;  谢谢你 Devin
Xcode 9 comes with over 100 new
Xcode 9 新增了 100 多个
errors and warnings to help find
错误和警告
bugs in your code.
来帮助在代码中发现 Bug
Let's talk about two warnings
接下来我们来说说
that are important for
两个对 Objective-C 很重要的
Objective-C.
警告
Under ARC, most parameters are
在 ARC 中 在块中捕捉大多数参数
safe to capture in blocks.
都很安全
In this example, the
在这个例子中
validateDictionary usingChecker
validateDictionary(usingChecker)
method takes an NSDictionary and
方法使用了 NSDictionary 并
visits every entry by calling
通过调用
enumerateKeysAndObjects
enumerateKeysAndObjectsUsingBlock
UsingBlock.
访问每个条目
Block captures the checker
块捕捉 checker
parameter.
参数
This is safe and works really
这个方法很安全 而且十分
well.
有效
Notice the checkObject forKey
注意 checkObject forKey
can fail.
可能会失败
The block sets stop to yes to
块将 stop 设置为“YES”
abort the enumeration early.
提前中止枚举
Since this is a validation
因为这是一个验证
method, it should also return
方法 所以应返回
BOOL and create an NS error.
BOOL 并生成一个 NSError
Let's make that change.
我们来改一下
OK. Let's walk through the code.
一起来看一下这个代码
Before enumerating, isValid is
在枚举之前 将 isValid
set to yes.
设置为“YES”
The block runs the checker and
块运行检查器 并
returns on success.
返回成功
If the checker fails, isValid is
如果检查器失效 isValid
set to no and an NS error is
设置为“NO” 一个 NSError
created.
将会产生
After enumerating, isValid is
枚举后 isValid
returned, but there's a bug
返回 但这里有一个
here.
Bug
Out parameters like error are
输出参数 比如错误
implicitly autoreleasing.
是隐性自动发布的
Assigning to them is not safe in
在块中为它们赋值
a block.
是不安全的
enumerateKeysAndObjects
enumerateKeysAndObjectsUsingBlock
UsingBlock calls the block
调用自动发布池
inside an autorelease pool.
中的块
When it returns, the NS error
当返回时 NSError
will get destroyed as well.
同时会被销毁
It isn't safe to use.
这个方法不安全
In Xcode 9, this unsafe capture
在 Xcode 9 中 这个不安全捕捉
will trigger a warning.
会触发警告
The easiest fix is to make the
最简单的解决方案是使
out parameter a strong
输出参数变成
reference.
强引用
This will keep the value alive
这样方法能使值
across any autorelease pools.
在任何自动发布池中一直存在
This works as long as all
这个方法能一直奏效 只要
callers of validateDictionary
validateDictionaryUsingChecker 的所有调用器
usingChecker are using ARC.
在使用 ARC
The other option is to use a
另一个选择是使用
local block variable.
本地块变量
Here strongError is initialized
在这个方法中 strongError（强错误）被初始化为
to nil.
“nil”
If the enumeration stops early,
如果枚举很早结束
strongError safely stores the NS
strongError 会安全地存储
error.
NSError
Then, the out parameter is
然后 输出参数
updated after the enumeration is
在枚举完成之后
complete.
完成升级
That's the first warning.
这是第一个警告
Let's move on to the second.
接下来我们介绍第二个警告
In this example, the function
在这个例子中 foo() 函数
foo is declared without any
声明没有任何
parameters.
参数
In C and Objective-C, that means
在 C 和 Objective-C 中 这意味着
that foo can be called with any
foo() 可以和
number or type of argument.
任何数或参数类调用
A function with an empty
参数列表为空的函数
parameter list is called a
叫做
non-prototype declaration.
非原型声明
This behavior dates from the
这个行为可以追溯至
early days of C where parameters
C 语言早期 当时参数
were only listed at function
只列在函数
definitions, but this
定义里 但是这个
declaration is not type safe.
声明对于类来说并不安全
This is never really what you
这绝对不会是
want.
你想要的
Calls that don't match the
不匹配定义的调用
definition can crash at runtime.
会导致运行时崩溃
In Xcode 9, the compiler has a
在 Xcode 9 中 编译器带有一个
new warning that enforces strict
新的警告 加强严格
prototypes.
原型
Usually, the fix is to add void.
通常 解决方法是添加空
This specifies exactly zero
也就是“0”
parameters.
参数
Any calls with arguments will
任何带有参数的调用都会
give an error.
引发错误
Since function pointers and
由于函数指针和块
blocks have a common declaration
对于函数有
syntax with functions, you'll
公用声明语法函数
also see this if you have a
如果你有以块作为
function or method that takes a
参数的函数或者方法
block as an argument.
你也会看到这个
The fix is the same as with
解决方法和
function declarations.
函数声明一样
Add void to specify exactly zero
添加空 明确规定“0”
parameters.
参数
Then, you'll get an error if you
这样 如果你输入
pass in a block with the wrong
错误类的块 你就会得到一个
type.
错误
Xcode's project modernization
Xcode 的现代化项目
will turn these warnings on in
会在构建设置中开启这些警告
your Build settings, or you can
或者你可以
upgrade later by selecting your
随后通过选择项目
project and choosing Validate
在“Editor（编辑器）”菜单中选择
Settings from the Editor menu.
“Validate Settings（验证设置）”进行升级
You can also upgrade new
你还可以
warnings to errors by selecting
通过在构建设置中
Yes (Error) in the Build
选择“Yes (Error)”
settings.
升级新的错误警告
That's it today for new
以上就是今天关于新的
warnings.
警告功能的介绍
Let's move on to C++.
接下来我们介绍 C++
This year, we've put a lot of
今年 我们做了很多工作
effort into improving the C++
来改善
experience in Xcode.
Xcode 中的 C++ 体验
That includes refactoring
包括重构
support.
支持
We support a lot of operations.
我们支持很多操作
I'd like to give a short tour of
我带领大家简单了解一下
using Xcode to refactor LLVM.
利用 Xcode 重构 LLVM 的流程
This is a large C++ code base
这是一个大型 C++ 代码库
that shows off the engine.
这个是其引擎
But even if you're not a C++
但即使你不是一个 C++
developer, you could still get
开发人员 你仍然可以
an idea of how refactoring in
了解 Xcode 重构
Xcode can improve your work
如何能够改善你的
flow.
工作流
I started at a member function
我以 InstCombiner 类的
definition from the InstCombiner
一个成员函数定义
class.
开始
This is a utility for combining
这是组合指令的一个
instructions.
实用程序
I never liked the Inst short
我一直不喜欢
form for instruction, so I
指令的缩写形式 Inst  所以我
Command-clicked in Xcode and
在 Xcode 里按住 Command 键点按它
selected Rename.
并选择“Rename（重命名）”
This worked even though I wasn't
即使我不是在类声明中
at the class declaration.
这个方法依然有效
InstructionCombiner is more
我觉得指令组合这个名称
clear to me.
更加清楚
Xcode updated the name in place.
Xcode 更新了一个合适的名称
This saved me a lot of hunting
让我节省了很多
around.
寻找的时间
I double-checked the class
我再次确认了类
declaration.
声明
It was updated too.
它也升级了
So was its use in the CRTP base
它在 CRTP 基类中的使用也升级了
class, InstVisitor.
变成了 InstVisitor
InstVisitor uses the same short
InstVisitor 使用一样的
form, and so does
缩写
InstCombineWorklist.
InstCombineWorklist 也是
But I had better leave those for
但是这方面我最好留待
a separate commit.
下一次再介绍
Since changing a class name from
鉴于我们可以改变一个类的
one of its member functions
成员函数的名称
worked, I moved on to something
我接着操作
even more complicated.
更加复杂的流程
I went to a template
这是一个模板
specialization for simplified
特化的简化类
type, a utility we use on smart
一个用于智能
pointers and custom iterators.
指针和自定义迭代器上的实用程序
I think the function
我认为 getSimplifiedValue()
getSimplifiedValue is named
函数的命名
wrong.
是错误的
It should use STL naming
它应该使用 STL 命名
conventions like its class name.
惯例 正如它的类的名称一样
I selected Rename again.
我再次选择“Rename”
Tying together template
从项目中将模板特化
specializations from across the
绑到一起
project is complicated, but
很复杂 但是
Xcode can handle it.
Xcode 可以处理
The specialization I was looking
这个特化
at was updated and so was the
之前升级过
main template declaration.
主要模板声明也升级过
There's another specialization
这下面还有另一个特化
right below, and it was fixed
也经过了
too.
修正
Next, I moved to Constants.h,
接下来 我们来到 Constants.h
where we have a class called
这里有个类叫做
ConstantInt for representing
ConstantInt 代表
constant integers.
常量整数
It has nice convenience
这个类拥有便利
functions for getting true and
函数 能够得到真值和
false values.
假值
I added declarations for a
我给 getMax() 函数
getMax function to get the
添加了声明 以得到
maximum integer value.
最大整数值
Then, I Command-clicked and
然后我按住 Command 键并点按
generated the missing function
为它们生成缺失的
definitions for each of them.
函数定义
Here they are in Constants.cpp.
这时它们在 Constants.cpp 中
What I like about this is where
我喜欢它的地方在于
the functions showed up in the
函数显示在
file.
文件夹中的位置
My new definitions were
我的新定义
generated after the last member
在上一个成员
functions defined for the same
函数定义为同一类 ConstantInt 之后生成
class, ConstantInt, but before
但在成员函数
the member functions for the
定义为另一个类之前
next class.
生成
This is exactly where I want
这也正是我想要的
them.
结果
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
LVM has lots of code for
LLVM 有很多代表整数
representing integers.
的代码
I had a look at this greatest
我看了下这个最大
common divisor function, and I
公约数函数 然后
noticed a local variable, Pow2,
注意到一个本地变量 Pow2
that is complicated to
它的计算
calculate.
非常复杂
Its computation really belongs
这个计算真的应该归入
in its own function.
它自己的函数
I selected the code and opened
我挑了一些代码 打开
the contextual menu, where I
上下文菜单
clicked on Extract Function.
点按“Extract Function（提取函数）”
I was a little sloppy with my
挑选过程比较马虎
selection, but Xcode is smart
但是 Xcode 很聪明
enough that it worked anyway.
还是奏效了
That entered me straight into
这样我就直接进入了
rename at the bottom of the
屏幕底部的
screen.
重命名
I chose countCommonPowersOf2.
我选择 countCommonPowersOf2
Let's scroll up and look at the
我们向上滚动 看一下这个
definition.
定义
The key thing here is that the
这个关键就是
arguments A and B were
参数 A 和 B
automatically captured by
是自动
reference.
被引用捕捉的
That's important because they're
这一点很重要因为它们
being modified.
正在被修改
Extract Function got it right.
提取函数纠正了这个问题
Extracting the function was a
提取这个函数是一个
nice opportunity to clean up the
利用提前返回
code to use early returns.
清理代码的好机会
That got me bouncing around a
我很开心
little, and I found this code in
我在循环展开的
the optimizer for unrolling
优化程序中发现了
loops.
这个代码
I noticed a call to getLoopFor
我在一个 if 语句中
and an if statement.
发现了 getLoopFor() 的调用
The same function is called with
这个相同的函数再次被调用
the same argument again right
为相同的参数 就在下面的
below in a while loop.
一个 while 循环中
getLoopFor does a hash table
getLoopFor 做了一个散列表
lookup, which isn't free.
查询 这并不容易
Since the while loop doesn't
因为 while 循环不
change the hash table, I
改变散列表
Command-clicked and selected
我按住 Command 键点击它 选择
Extract Repeated Expression.
“Extract Repeated Expression（提取重复表达）”
This stored the result of the
这个方法将
function call in a local
函数调用的结果存储在本地
variable, so it was only called
变量中 所以只调用
once, and then I immediately
一次 接着我马上使用
used Rename.
重命名
I chose the name LoopLatch.
我选择了 LoopLatch 这个名称
That was easy.
很简单
Extract and Rename work cleanly
提取和重命名
together.
放在一起很清晰
After all that refactoring, I
重构之后 我
thought I'd write some new code.
觉得我需要写一些新的代码
ArrayRef is a generalized
ArrayRef 是一个
reference to contiguous values,
连续值的泛化引用
whether they're in an STL vector
无论是在 STL 矢量中
or in one of LVM's custom data
还是在 LLVM 自定义数据
structures.
结构中
Notice that ArrayRef is
注意 ArrayRef
templated on the value type in
数组中数值类的
the array.
模版化
I thought it might be useful to
我认为
compare two ArrayRefs.
比较两组 ArrayRefs 应该是有用的
Why not implement a string like
为什么不执行一个
comparison?
字符串一样的比较呢
I need to loop from zero to the
我需要从零循环至
minimum size between left-hand
左右之间
side and right-hand side.
的最小值
When I hit the dot after
当我点击
left-hand side, code completion
左边后面的点时 代码完成
kicked in.
开始生效
Remember, left-hand side is
请记住 左边是
templated on T here.
的模板化
That's pretty cool.
很酷
Code completion works with
代码完成可以利用
templates, new in Xcode 9.
模板 这是 Xcode 9 的新功能
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And that's C++ refactoring and
这就是 Xcode 的 C++ 重构和
code completion in Xcode.
代码完成
Let's talk about a few features
接下来我们来谈一谈
from the C++17 standard.
C++17 标准的新特点
I'll start with STL's tuple, a
我会从 STL 的元组开始
useful type from C++11 that
这个类来自于 C++11 非常有用
enables multiple return values.
它支持多个返回值
But decomposing it is awkward.
但是对它进行分解很麻烦
Decomposition requires a tie
分解需要
around the variables, the types
变量连结 类型
can't be inferred, and the
无法推理
variable names need to be
变量的名称需要
duplicated.
复制
C++17 solves this with
C++17 通过
structured binding, which binds
结构化绑定解决了这个问题
names directly to the returned
它将名称直接和
tuple elements.
返回元组元素绑定
This is a great feature.
这个功能很棒
Now, it's much easier to work
有了这个方法
with tuples.
利用元组将变得容易得多
Structured binding can be used
结构化绑定可以运用在
anywhere get can be used.
很多方面
It also works out of the box
它还可以以创新的方法
with plain-old data types like
运用在旧式数据类上 比如
Point.
Point
The syntax is exactly the same
语法和
as with tuples.
元组完全一样
That's structured binding.
以上是结构化绑定
The next feature is initializers
另一个功能是
in if statements.
if 语句中的初始化
Here's an example.
这里举个例子
The initializer finds the last
初始化程序
slash in a path string.
在路径字符串中找到了最后的斜杠
The slash variable scope is
斜杠变量范围
limited to the if statement.
限定在 if 语句中
Then, the condition checks
接着 条件检查
whether slash was found.
斜杠是否被找到
If so, then slash is used to
如果找到的话 斜杠将被用于
split the path.
切分路径
The same feature works for
这个功能也一样适用于
switch statements.
switch 语句
Minimizing the scope of the
最小化斜杠变量
slash variable helps to prevent
的范围有助于防止
bugs.
Bug
If this function continues,
如果函数继续
we'll get an error if we try to
如果我们尝试复用斜杠变量
reuse the slash variable.
会得到一个错误
This is good because the logic
这是好事 因为逻辑上这
is unrelated.
是不相关的
Let's move on to a feature for
接下来我们介绍
templated functions.
模板化函数的一个功能
Advance is a simple template
Advance 是一个简单的
algorithm for in advancing an
先行迭代器的模板
iterator.
算法
It has been in the STL for a
它已经配置在 STL 中很长时间了
long time, but let's use it as
今天我们把它作为
an example.
一个例子
For n greater than 0, it moves
一个大于 0 的 n 它推动
the iterator forward, and for n
迭代器向前 一个小于 0 的 n
less than 0, it moves the
它使
iterator backward.
迭代器后退
For example, you might want to
比如 你有时候可能想
look ahead five nodes in a
在一张链表中
linked list.
预先查看 5 个节点
Advance will count forward one
Advance 会一个一个
by one.
向前计数
The same code works for getting
相同的代码也可以用来得到
the fifth character in a string.
一个字符串的第五个字符
It's powerful to have the same
用相同的接口
interface for advancing in both
在两个数据结构中先行
data structures.
效果很好
But this code is really slow for
但是这个代码
strings.
在字符串中运行很慢
For strings in arrays, which
对于有随机访问迭代器的
have random access iterators, we
数组字符串
don't need a loop.
我们不需要循环
Operator + will jump ahead in
Operator + 会跳转到
concept time.
概念时
But adding a simple if statement
但是添加一个简单的 if 语句
won't work because it's just a
没有效果 因为它只是一个
runtime check.
运行时检查
Its body is required to compile
它的主体需要
for all template instantiations,
为所有模板实例化进行编译
but linked list iterators don't
但是链表迭代器不能
have operator +.
配置 Operator +
We have a problem.
我们面临一个问题
Advance needs a common interface
Advance 需要一个通用接口
that compiles for linked lists
为链表和字符串
and a fast path for strings and
和数组的快速路径
arrays.
进行编译
The classic solution is a
经典解决方法是
technique called compile time
一种叫做编译时
dispatch, where the logic is
派发的技术 其逻辑被
split into overloaded helper
分解成过载帮助函数
functions and advance calls the
且 Advance 基于
right overload based on a
编译时类特性调用
compile time type trait.
合适的过载
And compile time dispatch works.
编译时派发是有效的
It's what C++ Library authors
它也是 C++ 库的作者们
have been doing for decades.
努力工作了几十年的成果
But it's an advanced technique,
即使这是一个很先进的技术
and what we're trying to do is
我们要做的却
pretty simple.
非常简单
The original not working code
原先无效的代码
was easy to understand.
其实也很容易理解
In C++17, constexpr if allows
在 C++17 中 constexpr if 可以让
you to express this logic
你很自然地表达这个
naturally.
逻辑
constexpr if discards the not
constexpr if 在实例化模板时
taken paths when instantiating
删除了不用的路径
temples, so the linked list code
所以链表代码
will still compile, but advance
会继续编译 但是 Advance
will use the fast path for
会使用字符串和数组的
strings and arrays.
快速路径
constexpr if makes reading and
constexpr if 使得阅读和
writing generic code much
书写通用代码
simpler.
变得更加简单
Let's finish with a new library
最后在结束之前 我们介绍一个新的
facility for strings.
字符串程序库功能
The STL string class has a rich
STL 字符串类有着丰富的
API, but it's not always the
API 但它并不一直是
right tool.
合适的工具
This example might look
这个例子可能看起来
familiar.
有点眼熟
The function split searches for
这个函数切分用于寻找
the last slash in the path
路径参数的最后一个
argument.
斜杠
If it finds a slash, it splits
如果它找到斜杠 它会将
the path into directory and
路径切分为目录和
filename.
文件名
Without a slash, it returns the
当没有斜杠时 它会将
full path as the filename.
完整路径返回至文件名
Because of string's API, this
由于字符串的 API
code was easy to write, but
这个代码很容易编写
there's a performance problem
但是有性能方面的
lurking.
问题
Split is returning copies of the
切分返回了
string.
字符串的 copy
Heavy use of functions like
大量使用函数 比如 split()
split can introduce expensive
可能引发昂贵的
allocations.
配置问题
C++17 has a new facility for
C++17 有一个
referencing strings.
引用字符串的新功能
It's called string view.
叫做字符串视图
A string view encapsulates a raw
字符串视图封装未处理的
const char [inaudible] and a
const char * 和
size.
size_t
It has a rich API, just like
它有丰富的 API
string, so it's convenient for
就像字符串一样 所以很方便用于
string manipulation.
字符串处理
And as the name suggests, it's
而且顾名思义
just a view.
它只是一个视图
It doesn't own any storage, and
它没有任何存储
so it never makes a copy.
所以永远无法生成 copy
String view is great for
字符串视图
performance, but there is a
性能很好 但是
caveat: String view isn't always
有一个问题 字符串并不永远
safe.
都是安全的
Because it doesn't own its
因为它没有自己的
storage, using a string view
存储 在原始字符串破坏或修改后
after the original string is
使用字符串视图
destroyed or modified can cause
可能引发
a use after free.
UAF 问题
Referencing a raw string literal
引用原始字符串文字 如“resources/images”
like resources/images is always
一直很安全
safe because raw string literals
因为原始字符串文字
have the lifetime of the
有程序生命
program.
周期
Taking a string view as an
将字符串视图
argument is safe, but avoid
作为参数是安全的 但是需要避免
storing a string view argument
越过函数返回
past the function return.
存储字符串视图参数
Be careful of return values.
注意返回值
If a string view is derived from
如果字符串视图来自
an argument, it will be safe to
一个参数 那么使用它很安全
use as long as the argument
只要参数
isn't changed or destroyed.
不改变或不受到损坏
In this example, directory and
在这个例子里 使用目录和
filename are safe to use as long
文件名十分安全 只要
as path remains constant and
路径保持不变
valid.
保持有效
But if we replace path with a
但如果我们用计算字符串代替路径
computed string, then accessing
那么访问
either directory or filename
目录或文件
will cause a use after free.
都会引起 UAF 问题
The root cause is that split was
根本原因在于切分
passed a temporary.
越过了临时对象
The temporary is destroyed after
切分调用之后临时对象被损坏
the call to split, and its
而且其引用
references are invalidated.
变得无效
Accessing the temporary invokes
访问临时对象会引起
undefined behavior.
不明确的行为
AddressSanitizer can catch this
AddressSanitizer 可以捕捉这个
bug.
Bug
Watch Understanding Undefined
大家可以观看“Understanding Undefined Behavior”
Behavior to learn more about
了解更多关于这种 Bug 的信息
this kind of bug and Finding
还可以观看
Bugs Using Xcode Runtime Tools
“Finding Bugs Using Xcode Runtime Tools”
to learn about tools to combat
了解处理 Bug 的
them.
工具
String view is the last C++17
字符串视图是我今天
feature I'll show you today.
和大家分享的 C++17 的最后一个功能
To try out C++17, set the C++
为了测试 C++17
language dialect in your Build
在你的构建设置中
settings.
设置 C++ 语言
C++17 gives you the standardized
C++17 为你提供
language without extensions.
没有扩展名的标准化语言
GNU++17 adds the usual
GNU++17 添加了常用的
extensions.
拓展名
Now, I have a quick update on
现在 我快速地给大家介绍一下
link-time optimization.
关于链接时优化的更新
Link-time optimization, or LTO,
链接时优化 或简称 LTO
optimizes the executable at link
在链接时间内优化
time, blurring the line between
可执行文件模糊
source files and enabling
源文件之间的界限
powerful optimizations.
支持优化最大化
Incremental LTO, which we
去年我们介绍的
introduced last year, is the
增量式 LTO
state of the art.
已经代表了目前的最新技术水平
For more information, watch last
想要了解更多信息 请观看去年
year's talk, What's New in LLVM.
“What’s New in LLVM”的相关视频
In the past, when using LTO on
过去 在大型 C++ 程序中
large C++ programs, we've
使用 LTO 时 我们推荐更改
recommended changing the Debug
Debug Info Level Build
Info Level Build setting to Line
设置为
Tables Only.
Line Tables Only
But in Xcode 9, we took
但是在 Xcode 9 中 我们将
incremental LTO to the next
增量式 LTO 的技术
level.
提升到了一个新的水平
Let's look at the time to link
我们一起来看看链接
the Apple LLVM compiler itself.
Apple LLVM 编译器所需要的时间
In Xcode 8, a clean link with
在 Xcode 8 中 一个有着完整调试信息的干净链接
full debug info took almost six
需要 6 分钟
minutes.
的时间
Line Tables Only was
Line Tables Only 快了
three-and-a-half minutes faster.
3.5 分钟
We sped up incremental LTO with
Xcode 9 中配备完整调试信息
full debug info by 35% in Xcode
的增量式 LTO
9.
的速度快了 35%
Line Tables Only is still
Line Tables Only 还是更快
faster, but the overhead is now
但是现在只需要
only 90 seconds.
90 秒
That was a clean link.
这是干净的链接
The true power of incremental
增量式 LTO 的真正作用
LTO is its fast incremental
在于其快速的增量式
builds.
创建
When only one file changes, the
当只有一个文件夹改变时
link doesn't repeat
链接不会重复
optimizations unnecessarily.
不必要的优化
In Xcode 8, an incremental link
在 Xcode 8 中 一个 Apple LLVM 编译器
of the Apple LLVM compiler
配备有完整调试信息的
itself took 21 seconds with full
增量式链接
debug info, more than two times
只需要 21 秒
longer than Line Tables Only.
比 Line Tables Only 快了 2 倍多
This is why we recommended
这也是我们过去建议
changing the debug info level in
改变调试信息水平
the past.
的原因
But in Xcode 9, the same
但是在 Xcode 9 中 相同的
incremental link is
增量式链接
two-and-a-half times faster.
的速度快了 2.5 倍
At just over eight seconds, it's
只需要 8 秒
even faster than Line Tables
它甚至比
Only mode was last year.
去年的 Line Tables Only 模式还快
If you looked at incremental LTO
如果你过去考虑过增量式 LTO
but didn't want to change your
但是没想过改变你的
debug info level, it's time to
调试信息水平
look again.
那么现在是时候再次考虑了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
We recommend turning on
我们建议
incremental LTO today, even if
今天就开启增量式 LTO 即使
you're using full debug info.
你已经正在使用完整信息调试
So that's what's new in LLVM.
以上就是“What’s New In LLVM”的全部内容
Use @available to safely use new
使用 @available 确保
APIs when supporting older OS's.
在支持旧的 OS 时安全使用新的 API
Run the static analyzer while
创建时运行
you build.
静态分析器
Use Xcode to refactor your code.
使用 Xcode 重构代码
Try out the new features in
试试 C++17 的
C++17.
新功能
And turn on incremental LTO to
开启增量式 LTO
upgrade your performance without
升级性能 而不用
sacrificing incremental build
牺牲增量式创建
time.
时间
For more information, see the
想要了解更多信息 请登录
website.
我们的网站
I recommend you watch the
我建议各位观看我们的
related sessions.
相关会议
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]